Oh
See you
next time.
Aaaaaaah!
Aaaaah! Aaaaaaah!
Seeking!
Exists!
Ooh!
Watch out, Iceberg!
Hey!
What in the hell is wrong with you?
Ow! Idiot!
Don't you know you're not supposed
to be goofing around right now?
We got real ships to work
on, not your crappy toys.
Don't yell at me when you don't have
a clue what you're talking about,
ice for brains.
It isn't some crappy toy.
It's my super battleship
that battled Franky.
Whatever it is, you need to leave
it alone before someone gets hurt.
This is Scrap Heave Island.
I can do what I want.
Wait, you'll see.
I'm going to build a battleship
awesome enough to take down a Sea King.
Bull, what you're going to
do is get yourself killed.
Oh, yeah? Yeah, quick. Nuh-uh. Real quick.
If you want to be a man, show some gusto.
Well, there's the old launching ceremony.
One more ship sailing with gusto.
Ha, ha, ha! Right, buddy?
Giddle, giddle, giddle.
That's about enough work for today.
What do you say we head on home?
Giddle, giddle.
Man, I'm hungry. Giddle, giddle.
Let's see what's for dinner.
Giddle, giddle.
Hey, hold on!
Wait for us!
So today's Battle Franky model
was number, what are you up to?
Ain't, sir.
It was really beautiful. No, it wasn't.
Your dumb weapon that he let
you build for some reason
fell apart after you almost
killed both of us with it.
Nobody asked you, you
stupid ice for brains.
Ice for brains?
Well, you're flunky!
All right, that's enough
fighting, boys. Cut it out.
He started it, not me.
My word.
Don't encourage those two, Tom.
Was it that funny?
Keep laughing.
And they'll keep misbehaving.
Speaking of misbehaving,
I heard that another ship carrying
lumber was attacked by pirates.
I swear, ever since the king
of the pirates was executed,
this place has just gone
rotten with those Newgate bums.
They're taking over the city.
The people's spirits are really low.
And because of all the
flooding from Aqualaguna,
we can only get lumber and iron if
we ship them in from other islands.
But with all the storms and pirates
everywhere, it's near impossible.
The shipyards are starting to
get so desperate for customers,
they are literally fighting
each other for them.
So many have closed down already.
At this rate,
Water 7 is on a course to sink into the
ocean and fade from the world's memory.
And to think, this city made
its name, making unforgettable,
unsinkable ships such a shame.
Hey, you built a big, super awesome
pirate ship once now, didn't you, Tom?
Will you teach me how to draw
out blueprints for one, too?
What's so funny, huh?
Franky, there's no such thing
as blueprints for a pirate ship.
It's the flag, boy.
Skull and bones means pirate ship,
and a Skull flag means that it's navy.
Whatever you build, just remember this.
Build it with pride.
And a whole lot of manly gusto!
You sure are working late tonight.
What are you drawing?
This here is hope for our island
It is? Yep.
Well, at least that's what I'm
hoping that it'll turn into someday!
Now, to bed with ya.
Yes, sir.
Huh?
Whoa! Whoa.
The judicial ship is here.
What the heck is that?
A mobile court.
I wonder who they're here for.
What do you think you're doing?
Let him go, you big stupid jerk.
He didn't do anything wrong.
Don't you worry.
I'll be just fine.
No, Tom!
Come back!
Justice was brought to Gold Roger, the
king of the pirates, by way of execution.
His ship, the Oro Jackson,
was built by none other than Tom,
who stands before this court today.
As penalty for aiding and
abetting that vicious criminal,
Tom will be taken to Ennie's
lobby where he will be executed.
No.
The verdict was read. Guilty.
They're going to execute Tom.
They say it's because he built a
ship for the king of the pirates.
Damn shame.
That thing brought a whole
lot of grief into the world.
Now, building ships is not a crime,
and one may sell them to almost
anyone who wishes to buy,
but we must make an exception
for the king of the pirates.
On the charge of providing
meaningful assistance
to the man who terrorized
the entire world,
we hereby sentence Tom to death.
Take him away.
Come on, time to go. Move it.
You heard him.
Hurry up.
Go already.
Hey, what are you doing?
I've got a new design for a
completely new kind of paddle steamer.
A train that will run on the
surface of the ocean with gusto.
Shut up. Get moving.
This once great island has lost its gusto.
Our trade is not what it used to be.
People have lost hope.
Water 7 is slowly sinking away.
Every day, our hard-working
citizens are filled with worry.
I can lift their spirits!
I will!
By building our good people a Sea Train!
Quit flapping your gums
and move your feet!
No, let him stay.
Sea Train.
Tell me more.
It's like a ship, but one that
puffs out steam and runs on a track.
It'll go between the islands, carrying
people and all kinds of goods,
even other ships.
Most importantly, it won't be
affected by conditions at sea.
That's ridiculous.
A railway on the water will be ripped
to pieces once Aqualaguna comes around.
And even if it doesn't, what are you going
to do about all the sea kings out there?
It doesn't have to be a
completely fixed track.
Huh?
It'll be submerged under the water a bit,
so it won't be bombarded by the waves.
It'll sway, just like a rope in the water.
The Sea Train will just use the tracks
as a guide to get from place to place.
I'm also considering installing
a mechanism that emits a loud,
dissonant sound underwater to discourage
fish from getting anywhere near the tracks.
It should work on sea kings as
well, so they won't pose a threat.
Whoa, is all that possible?
If we connect St.
Poplar, Pucci,
Sanfaldo, and this island,
we can create a booming economy
that will help out all of us.
Amazing.
I will be finished with
the blueprints very soon,
but it will take a master
shipwright to build it.
Now, could the Sea Train run
to Annie's lobby as well?
Without a doubt, Your Honor.
Once the plans are in the can
and the railway is in the water,
people can go with gusto from
island to island for work or play.
And once again, Water 7 will
be a city filled with hope.
How long will it take?
Ten years.
Then build it.
If you agree to develop this Sea Train,
I will give you the time to do it.
Consider these next
ten years as probation.
That's great news.
Good luck, Tom.
Save Water 7, please.
Ah, gusto.
I'm alive!
I'm glad you think this is so funny.
I thought you were a goner.
I was worried sick over you.
But I guess if this
plan of yours works out,
they're willing to forgive and
forget the whole Gold Roger affair.
Well, I just got to tell you
how amazed I am with you, Tom.
What a great idea!
It's unbelievable to think you could
just come up with that on your own.
It's brilliant when you told...
Thanks for the grub.
Come on, Yokozuna.
I'll teach you the front crawl.
Hey, we're all celebrating
here, and you want to leave?
What's your deal?
My deal?
What happened to Tom was so unfair!
He built the only ship that was
able to sail the whole Grand Line,
something no one else
in the world could do!
And those jerks want to
put him to death over it?
They don't realize how hard that is!
They couldn't even string together a
raft if their lives depended on it!
I mean,
I know that the whole reason our
office is under this bridge is
because those stupid people kicked
you out of town over that ship!
You're the greatest
shipbuilder the world has
ever known and they
treat you like garbage!
What are you laughing at,
you big yellow weirdo?
You're crazy!
Stop attacking him, you stupid kid!
Why does he have to laugh at everything?
No, no, no!
You're doing it wrong!
Stroke harder and push that water back!
No, no! Do it harder! Don't hold back!
That Frankie's got a lot of nerve.
If I were you, I'd kick him
out for what he just did.
Well, I know the boy can be a handful,
but he's a fellow shipbuilder
at his young age He's
almost on par with the best
craftsman on the island.
He does build battleships.
Yeah
His problem is he's too honest.
Two years ago, I met that
kid on Scrap Heap Island.
He'd gone there to collect
junk to make a cannon.
It was firing it with Gusto
Old guy! Hey! Help me out!
My good-for-nothing parents ditched me!
Apparently his folks couldn't
handle his rambunctious behavior,
so they threw him off their ship.
Sounds like a couple of
heartless pirates to me, eh?
What a joke!
No, Tom.
He is one tough kid.
He's had a rough go at it, but
he's still got a good heart.
I'm positive that both
of you boys are going to
grow up to be world-class
shipwrights someday.
There's no need for you to be rivals.
I don't know about all that.
It's like he's allergic
to sanity or something.
Well,
I just need to finish those blueprints and
then we'll build ourselves a Sea Train.
Yeah, I bet he won't help at all.
He can do whatever he wants.
Thank you.
Suicide?
That's the word.
Head of the fourth largest shipyard.
What a tragic story.
They ran out of materials, so he took
a ship out to sea to get some more.
Lost 50 men on the water.
They had to close down his shop.
Oh, man.
Will this be how it ends?
Is this how Water 7 finally dies?
Hey!
Did you guys hear?
Big news from Scrap Heap Island!
No way.
Did they do it?
Did Tom's workers actually
finish the Sea Train?
Whoa!
Is this crazy thing really gonna work?
I don't know if I trust
something built by a criminal.
I'll try it out.
Yeah, what the heck, me too.
They gonna tell us how it works?
All aboard, ladies and gentlemen!
Whoa, the paddles have
grabbed at the railway!
Man, that is the coolest thing ever!
12 years ago,
departing from an isolated
city in decline and full of
passengers who've almost given
up hope for a brighter future,
the sea
train Puffing
Tom embarked on its maiden
interesting many ships were born in this
cobwebbed room and now look at it filthy
they built ships here
tom iceberg and cutty
flam this place must hold
countless memories of
days when you still shared
a life with those two
and now you call it your
top secret base that's
heartbreakingly adorable
damn you just get the
hell out of here already
we won't leave till we
get what we're after make
this easy on yourself
there ain't no blueprints
in here oh no you don't
say just keep it
together you
bastard take
your time but be aware that we know many
things about your past things that you
don't want getting out for example we know
what happened eight years ago And that you
are guilty of committing a very serious
crime back then just
like your dear old Tom
You shut up Tom was never a damn criminal.
You don't know what the
hell you're talking about.
You freak
Tom!
Stay back!
I disagree.
You're both criminals.
And as such, you should be made to
feel the consequences of your actions.
Franky, whatever happens, don't
interfere with what I'm about to do,
no matter what.
You talk like you know everything.
You don't know Tom and you don't
know anything about Water 7.
I heard the judicial ship
will be here in three days.
Finally putting Tom on trial are they?
I hope it ends well for him.
I'm sure it will.
Right.
He fulfilled his promise, after all.
That he did.
All right, let's get
that lumber in the dock.
So, how'd the deal work out with St.
Poplar?
Not that great.
They're taking advantage of us since
we don't have much to trade with them.
Like iron from San Faldo.
We'll all be in the red if
this kind of crap keeps up.
We're not going to let this keep
happening now, are we, guys?
Yeah!
No way!
The people do seem to be happy
about being able to cross the ocean
but they say the trade situation
isn't as good as they'd hoped.
I wonder if this town needs
more than a Sea Train.
But their spirits are up.
Boy, that's a major step.
So give the rest some time.
We've done our best.
So be proud.
Keep your head held high
and walk with gusto.
Yeah.
You there?
Am I correct in assuming
I'm speaking with Mr.
Tom, the shipbuilding engineer?
You're a difficult man to pin down.
I have some matter of
great importance I wish to.
Sir, this man and I are talking. Yes, sir.
Again, before I was so rudely?
I was going to say,
my name is Agent Spandam
from Cipher Pole number five!
Stop it, sir!
Wow!
Sorry about that. My bad.
Looks like you got in the way
of my victory cannon salute.
Tough luck?
It's super!
Battle Franky 35 comes home with booty.
That's right, check it out!
Is this not the biggest sea
king you ever laid your eyes on?
I can't believe him,
still acting like a child.
Hey!
What the hell do you think
you're doing, ice for brains?
Will you ever grow up?
Ever since you were a kid, all you want
to do is build these stupid battleships.
It's time to stop.
This better be the last one, or I'm going
to start tearing them all apart myself.
Want a vet?
You lay a finger on my ship, and
you'll draw back a stump, you hear me?
Yeah? Well, listen Franky,
if you were able to kill a sea king
with this floating piece of junk,
that means it's a dangerous weapon.
And you've got all those other battleships
of yours just strewn around here?
What are you thinking?
Hey, it's not like I'm attacking
people with them, am I?
I'm not saying you'd do that,
but you're making it easier for
anyone else who'd want to, you idiot!
Am I right?
Back me up here, Tom.
Flunky's weapons are going to
be the end of our business.
Flunky! That's rich! Hold on!
This is no laughing matter!
I demand a sincere apology and that you
listen to what I've come here to say!
Government guy, are you?
So, is this about the trial? Trial?
What the devil are you talking about?
No, this concerns an
altogether different matter.
Did Tom come back with you boys
no I think he's with a visitor
Some man from the government
it wasn't about the tribe spawn
spawn something Spawn something
dumb maybe how strange and he's
not from the judicial ship The
government is so disorganized
Afraid not I've got no blueprints
for something like that
that's nonsense do you take
me for some kind of weak
-minded simpleton i researched
the history of Water 7 for
countless hours and i am absolutely
certain this document can
only be in your possession you're
saying that you actually have
the authority to investigate
me that's right i do and what's
more i learned all about your
dealings with gold roger in the
course of my investigation so
unless you want me to share
that information with my colleagues
you're going to cooperate.
Why would I care?
The government already knows about it.
We do?
That's such a poppycock.
If that's true, why are you here
and not rotting away somewhere?
in a jail cell?
Use your investigative powers
and find out for yourself.
Good day.
Hey, you can't treat a
government agent like this.
Open this door immediately.
That's right.
It's all true.
Yes, sir.
He did exactly what he
told the judge he'd do.
and they should be dropping the
charges at the trial that's coming up.
That man saved this island, for sure.
It makes my blood boil to think that damn
criminal is being treated like a hero.
I see.
You're certain that such a
thing truly exists? Yes, sir.
And the pirates are scouring
the globe for it as we speak.
That's why it's imperative
we locate it immediately.
If it were to fall into the wrong hands,
the resulting destruction
would be inconceivable.
We've been suffering through this great
pirate era for more than a decade now.
It's a vile sickness that grows
worse with every passing day.
The time for idle discussion is over.
We must do more than to prevent
this weapon's construction.
We must build it ourselves and use
it as a mighty instrument of justice!
With it,
we can eliminate this pirate scourge and
bring law and order back to our land!
This is indeed a troubling error.
There's no doubt about that.
Your primary objective will be to
locate and then obtain these blueprints.
That will be all at this time.
We trust that you can complete
this mission, Spandam.
Yes, sir! Without fail!
I've been working on this case for far
too long to see it all go up in smoke.
It's right within my grasp now.
Let's go!
Damn!
If the judge decides to acquit him,
that'll mean a real headache for me!
Spot him, sir!
The charge will stick, and
that bastard will hang.
Men, I'll need five more agents, stat!
Oh, no, sir!
Iceberg, Franky. Yeah?
Hey, boys, come here. What's up?
It's about time I let you
in on something important.
Why would anyone even dream
of something like this?
Is this for real?
Can this thing actually be built?
Those are the blueprints for
a nightmare, a real monster.
The government has
learned of their existence
and has started sniffing around for them.
It's too dangerous for
me to keep them anymore.
This is terrifying, but I agree.
I'll keep them.
Iceberg!
Hey, let's see if we can
build this thing! You idiot!
Do you ever think before you speak,
this thing can never be built?
Do you realize how much
destruction it could cause?
Yeah, the world would be done for.
Besides trying to build the damn thing,
you can do whatever the hell
you want with it for now.
Even toss it if you need to.
Yes, of course.
While I got your attention,
here's another storm a-brewin'.